Alan Trapenard



alan.trapenard@gmail.com



3104085105



linkedin.com/in/alan-trapenard-790670199



https://atrapenard.github.io/portfolio-website

Summary

San Diego based aspiring ML Engineer/Data Scientist.

5 years of experience with 4 years in Data Science and 1 year working with Supervised/Unsupervised ML Algorithms.

Experienced with working on Financial Data and performing Quantitative Analysis on stock market data. Career Highlight: Working with data from the state of Connecticut to analyze/model drug overdose trends.

If you are interested in any of the work I do or any projects I'm currently working on, my GitHub is GitHub.com/ ATrapenard

Experience

Quantitative Analyst

Sustainable Investment Group at UC San Diego

Mar 2023 - Present (7 months)

Work with members of different internal groups (Sustainability Analysis, Equity Research, etc.) to create comprehensive financial and sustainability-focused models of company performance. These models are subsequently used to inform Buy, Sell, or Hold recommendations and are pitched to CFA-Certified Judges.

Personal Responsibilities Include:

Assisting interns with learning and applying necessary algorithms/concepts for modeling

Create Rolling Sharpe Regression plots

Perform in-depth market analysis using a plethora of financial/data science libraries for Python. (Pandas, NumPy, Pytorch, yfinance, and internal libraries)

Participate in the stock-pitch competition once every quarter. This includes presenting all models created and being able to answer any questions posed by Judges with regard to standalone models as well as how the models serve to bolster the information presented by the rest of the team.



Self Employed

Self Employed

Jan 2016 - Present (7 years 9 months)

Providing freelance Software/Website Design services as well as Lighting Design and Sound Design Services by contract to theatre and dance companies and studios in the Greater San Diego Area.



Crew Member

Mendocino Farms

Customer Service Representative

Teuscher Chocolates of Switzerland San Diego Jul 2020 - Jan 2022 (1 year 7 months)

Customer Service Representative

CVS Health

May 2019 - Oct 2019 (6 months)

Operated POS systems.

Stocked shelves.

Processed returns and photo orders.

Organized the store before closing.

Rotated merchandise depending on season.

Education



UC San Diego

Bachelor of Science - BS, Machine Learning and Neural Computation Sep 2019 - Jun 2023



🚵 La Jolla High School

High School Diploma, Chemistry 2015 - 2019

Skills

Refinitiv • Applied Machine Learning • Scikit-Learn • Yfinance • Python (Programming Language) • JavaScript • React.js • React Native • HTML • HTML5